Saying that...
Habiendo dicho eso...
I'm starting to appreciate again just how important she is.
Vuelvo a apreciar lo importante que ella es.
"She"?
¿"Ella"?
But we haven't heard from her since the Ajisai Cup.
Pero no escuchamos de ella desde la Copa Ajisai.
I say it's eerie how we ain't heard from her.
Es realmente inquietante que no hayamos oído de ella.
From that highfalutin heiress.
De esa presuntuosa señorita.
Tokunaga.
Tokunaga.
Miss?
¿Sí?
I'm going to take a bath.
Me daré un baño.
I need to remove ten months of accumulated grime from my stay on that mountain.
Tengo que eliminar la mugre acumulada por diez meses en la montaña.
Once We Graduate...
"Después de graduarnos..."
Sign: All Sports News Daily#
#Todos los Deportes
You call this a story?
¿Esto te parece una historia?
You don't seem very enthused about your work lately.
Últimamente no pareces entusiasmado por tu trabajo.
What the hell happened?
¿Qué diablos sucedió?
No kidding!
Es verdad.
Kosaku has been feeling down lately.
Kosaku se nota deprimido últimamente.
I even invited him for yakiniku to cheer him up, but he acted like he didn't hear me!
Incluso lo invité a comer para alegrarlo, pero hizo como si no me escuchara.
What? It still eats you that Inokuma Yawara won't be transferring to Saikai U?
¿Qué? ¿Todavía te molesta que Yawara Inokuma no se transferirá a Saikai?
Plus Tsurukame Travel, a no-name company without a judo team, snatched her away,
Además, Viajes Tsurukame, una empresa desconocida sin equipo de judo, la atrapó.
which makes a dull story?
¿Por eso tu historia es aburrida?
Moping all the time won't change a damn thing!
¡Lamentarte todo el tiempo no cambiará nada!
I see. Can you offer a comment?
Ya veo. ¿Puedes hacer algún comentario?
Inokuma Yawara is graduating from Mitsuba today.
Yawara Inokuma se gradúa hoy de Mitsuba.
You sure you don't want to go?
¿Seguro no quieres ir?
Don't worry, Chief.
No te preocupes, jefe.
Kosaku has absolutely no interest in Yawara-chan's new career.
A Kosaku no le interesa para nada la nueva carrera de Yawara.
If she'd gone to Barcelona and won a gold medal for him,
Si hubiese ido a Barcelona a ganar una medalla de oro para él,
that would've made a good article, right, Kosaku?
eso habría sido un buen artículo, ¿no es así, Kosaku?
He's finally out of the picture.
Finalmente está fuera.
I can't believe Matsuda-san got incensed...
No puedo creer que Matsuda se haya enfurecido...
and told her himself that he was only chasing her for the articles.
... y le haya dicho él mismo que sólo la seguía por los artículos.
His words would sour even a hundred-year romance.
Esas palabras arruinarían hasta un romance de cien años.
Well, he's an amateur after all.
Bueno, después de todo, es un novato.
Matsuda-san was never a meaningful love rival.
Matsuda nunca fue un rival de cuidado.
Right now, Kazamatsuri Shinnosuke will snatch you all for himself.
Ahora, yo, Shinnosuke Kazamatsuri, te atraparé.
Yawara-san...
Yawara...
Congratulations on graduating from MWJC!
¡Felicitaciones por tu graduación de Mitsuba!
Sign: Mitsuba Women's Junior College Graduation Ceremony#
#Universidad para Mujeres Mitsuba #Ceremonia de graduación
I implore every one of you to take to heart the fact that women
Y les imploro a cada una de ustedes que consideren un hecho que las mujeres moldearán
will mold our society for generations to come.
nuestra sociedad en las generaciones venideras.
When you enter that society as Mitsuba Women's Junior College graduates...
Cuando ingresen en la sociedad como graduadas de la Universidad Mitsuba...
I can't. There goes my stomach! I'm going to die! When you enter that society as Mitsuba Women's Junior College graduates...
No puedo más. ¡Mi estómago! ¡Voy a morir!
Yoshinagawa-san, let's go eat some red bean soup when this is over.
Yoshinagawa, vayamos a comer una sopa de azuki cuando esto termine.
Red bean soup?
¿Sopa de azuki?
Red bean soup!
¡Sopa de azuki!
...doing so is very important.
... eso es muy importante.
Whatever you accomplish... love,
No importan lo que logren... El amor....
love is something you cannot forget.
&No pueden olvidar el amor.
This is a long speech, Inokuma-san.
&Es un discurso muy largo, Inokuma.
Love comes first.
&El amor es lo primero.
Yes.
&Sí.
Love comes second.
&El amor también es lo segundo.
It may have seemed long...
Pudo haber parecido mucho tiempo...
Love will continue to be of importance...
&El amor seguirá siendo importante...
but...
pero...
it all went by so fast.
Sucedió demasiado rápido.
It did.
Así es.
Ah, the unforgettable dream where they touched shoulders Ah ochibamau koutei de kata wo yose
%Ese sueño inolvidable donde sus hombros se tocaron
Sign: Mitsuba Women's Junior College Entrance Ceremony#
#Universidad para Mujeres Mitsuba #Ceremonia de graduación
and talked in the schoolyard amidst the falling leaves. katariatta yume wa ima mo wasurezu ni iru kedo Sign: Mitsuba Women's Junior College Entrance Ceremony#
%y hablaron en el patio mientras las hojas caían.
Ah, that song and the man she loved Ah suki datta ano uta mo ano hito mo
%Esa canción y el hombre que amó
Sign: Ito Fujiko# Ah, that song and the man she loved Ah suki datta ano uta mo ano hito mo
#Fujiko Itou
I'm... Sign: Ito Fujiko# Ah, that song and the man she loved Ah suki datta ano uta mo ano hito mo
Yo soy...
have dissolved in the fall sky as memories omoide ni kawatte aki no sora ni toketa
%se disolvieron como recuerdos en el cielo de otoño.
Ito Fujiko. have dissolved in the fall sky as memories omoide ni kawatte aki no sora ni toketa
Fujiko Itou.
And you are? have dissolved in the fall sky as memories omoide ni kawatte aki no sora ni toketa
¿Y tú?
I'm... have dissolved in the fall sky as memories omoide ni kawatte aki no sora ni toketa
Yo soy...
Sign: Inokuma Yawara# have dissolved in the fall sky as memories omoide ni kawatte aki no sora ni toketa
#Yawara Inokuma
Inokuma Yawara. Sign: Inokuma Yawara# have dissolved in the fall sky as memories omoide ni kawatte aki no sora ni toketa
Yawara Inokuma.
She has spent sleepless nights caught up kanawanu koi ni nagasarete
%Pasó incontables noches en vela
in a love that will remain unfulfilled. nemurenu yoru mo sugoshita kedo
%atrapada en un amor que no se realizará.
But she will kimochi wa
%Pero ella siempre
always wear a smile and bid farewell to her tears. itsudemo hohoemi wo nakimushi ni sayonara
%sonreirá y se despedirá de sus lágrimas.
I wanted to dance on the world stage. always wear a smile and bid farewell to her tears. itsudemo hohoemi wo nakimushi ni sayonara
En verdad quería bailar por todo el mundo.
But I know you can do that.
Pero tú sí puedes.
Everyone falls in love and grows up. daredemo koi wo shite otona ni naru no yo But I know you can do that.
%Todos se enamoran y maduran.
I know it can happen for you! daredemo koi wo shite otona ni naru no yo Everyone falls in love and grows up.
Tú puedes hacer realidad mi sueño.
Fujiko-san. daredemo koi wo shite otona ni naru no yo Everyone falls in love and grows up.
Fujiko.
Ah, the girls in class sparkled like gold Ah kin'iro ni kagayaita shoujotachi
%Las chicas brillaban como el oro
Book: The Gentle Way Isn't Built in a Day By Inokuma Jigoro# Ah, the girls in class sparkled like gold Ah kin'iro ni kagayaita shoujotachi
#El judo no se construye en tan sólo un día #Jigoro Inokuma
as they talked about their loves. oshaberi wo shinaraga otagai no koi no yukue wo
%cuando hablaban sobre sus amores.
Ah, there she was, in the corner by the window Ah kyoushitsu no katasumi de uranatte
%Ahí estaba, en la esquina cerca de la ventana
divining her fortunes and sighing many times. madobe de wa ikutsu mo tameiki wo otoshita
%adivinando su futuro y suspirando.
The girl whose tiny heart was so easily swayed chiisana mune wo odorasete
%La chica cuyo pequeño corazón cambiaba fácilmente
Well, I... you see... The girl whose tiny heart was so easily swayed chiisana mune wo odorasete
Nunca antes me sentí así.
It's like there's something burning in my chest. The girl whose tiny heart was so easily swayed chiisana mune wo odorasete
Es como si algo se quemara en mi pecho.
So I think I'll compete in this match.
Por eso creo que participaré en este encuentro.
while chasing after her first love. hajimete no koi oikaketeta So I think I'll compete in this match.
%mientras perseguía su primer amor.
She leaned in ano ko wa
%Ella se acercó
to give her beloved a farewell kiss, itoshii ano hito ni owakare no kuchidzuke
%para darle un beso de despedida a su amor,
We lost, didn't we? to give her beloved a farewell kiss, itoshii ano hito ni owakare no kuchidzuke
Perdimos, ¿no es así?
It doesn't matter anymore. to give her beloved a farewell kiss, itoshii ano hito ni owakare no kuchidzuke
Eso no importa.
Of course it does! Aren't you pissed?! to give her beloved a farewell kiss, itoshii ano hito ni owakare no kuchidzuke
¡Cómo que no importa! ¿Acaso no estás molesta?
as she concealed the tears in her heart. namida wo hitoshizuku kokoro ni kakushita Of course it does! Aren't you pissed?!
%mientras escondía las lágrimas de su corazón.
I'm also disappointed! namida wo hitoshizuku kokoro ni kakushita as she concealed the tears in her heart.
Yo también estoy molesta.
All right, let's go out there and fight!
¡Muy bien, salgamos a luchar!
Yeah!
¡Sí!
She gave her beloved a farewell kiss, itoshii ano hito ni owakare no kuchidzuke
%Le dio un beso de despedida a su amor,
as she concealed the tears in her heart. namida wo hitoshizuku kokoro ni kakushita
%mientras escondía las lágrimas de su corazón.
Un! as she concealed the tears in her heart. namida wo hitoshizuku kokoro ni kakushita
¡Un!
Deux! as she concealed the tears in her heart. namida wo hitoshizuku kokoro ni kakushita
¡Dos!
Trois! as she concealed the tears in her heart. namida wo hitoshizuku kokoro ni kakushita
¡Tres!
Oh, she'll always wear a smile and bid farewell to her tears. Oh itsudemo hohoemi wo nakimushi ni sayonara Trois!
%Ella siempre sonríe y se despidió de sus lágrimas.
Everybody falls in love and grows up dare demo koi wo shite otona ni naru no yo
%Todos se enamoran y maduran
toward a hopeful tomorrow. kibou no ashita e
%hacia un mañana lleno de esperanza.
It's all thanks to you.
Es todo gracias a ti.
I was unable to practice ballet anymore, and my life had no meaning.
Ya no podía practicar ballet, mi vida no tenía sentido.
However, a wonderful sport called judo has allowed me to graduate with a purpose in life.
Sin embargo, un maravilloso deporte llamado judo me permitió graduarme con un propósito.
Thank you...
Gracias...
Inokuma-san!
¡Inokuma!
Fujiko-san. If it weren't for you...
Fujiko. Si no hubiese sido por ti...
I want to thank you too.
Yo también quiero agradecerte.
Kyonkyon.
Kyon-Kyon.
I've become strong and cheerful because of you, Inokuma-san.
Me he vuelto fuerte y alegre gracias a ti, Inokuma.
I'll... I'll... never forget my debt to you!
Yo.. Yo... ¡Nunca olvidaré lo mucho que te debo!
Gosh, Kyonkyon...
Cielos, Kyon-Kyon...
Yawara-chan, we'll still see each other even after graduation, right?
Yawara, nos seguiremos viendo después de la graduación, ¿no es así?
I'm becoming a policewoman, so you need to teach me more judo, okay?
Seré policía, así que debes enseñarme mucho más acerca del judo.
Yeah.
Sí.
I lost so much weight thanks to you!
Yo perdí mucho peso gracias a ti.
I also have something to say.
Yo también quiero decirles algo.
Thank you all very much.
Muchas gracias a todas.
I'm starting to feel sentimental.
Hacen que me ponga sentimental.
Masaharu!
¡Masaharu!
Marilyn!
¡Marilyn!
"Masaharu"?
¿"Masaharu"?
He's just some guy who's giving me a ride.
Es sólo alguien que me acercará a casa.
Looks like a horndog. You know he's after your body.
Parece un pervertido. Sabes que sólo quiere tu cuerpo.
Too bad you don't have a guy to pick you up after your graduation.
Es una lástima que tú no tienes a nadie que te busque al terminar la graduación.
I've got one waiting right there!
¡Hay uno que me espera ahí mismo!
Yoko!
¡Yoko!
So if he dumps you, will that make him your 20th ex?
Entonces si te deja, ¿el se convertirá en el número 20?
How rude. He'd only be my 19th.
No seas grosera. Es el 19.
We're leaving now.
Nos vamos.
Let's have an awesome thank-you party later!
¡Luego haremos una fiesta!
You have weird taste!
Tus gustos son raros.
Still better than yours!
Pero mejor que los tuyos.
Oh, my gosh! Look at all those cars!
¡Increíble! ¡Mira esos autos!
Are they all here to pick someone up?
¿Todos vinieron a recoger a alguien?
Maybe we should get some tea.
Tal vez deberíamos ir a tomar el té.
Um, I actually...
De hecho yo...
U-Uh, this is Yoshida-san, a caregiver I met while doing pre-school training.
Les presento a Yoshida, lo conocí durante mi entrenamiento para el preescolar.
This is his friend, Kimura-kun.
Este es mi amigo, Kimura.
So, I guess you can call it a group acquaintance.
@Supongo que es una presentación en grupo.
Hi, nice to meet you.
Hola, encantado.
We've heard so much about you two.
Hemos escuchado tanto de ustedes.
Nice to meet you too.
Igualmente.
Thanks for looking after our friends.
Gracias por cuidar a nuestras amigas.
W-We'll be seeing you!
¡Hasta luego!
Congratulations.
Felicitaciones.
Thank you.
Gracias.
Here I am!
¡Aquí estoy!
Now listen here!
¡Escúchame!
I'm busy right now!
¡Ahora estoy ocupado!
Shin-chan, you have a date with yet another woman, don't you?
Tienes una cita con otra mujer, ¿no es así, Shin?
Of course not! I have work to do — work!
¡Por supuesto que no! ¡Es el trabajo! El trabajo.
Right now, you're the only one, Mayumi.
Tú eres la única, Mayumi.
Bye!
¡Hasta luego!
Hey, wait!
Espera un poco.
Look, I have to leave right now.
Escucha, debo irme ahora mismo.
Is your work more important than me?
¿Tu trabajo es más importante que yo?
N-No, you're more important!
Claro que no, tú eres más importante.
Geez, will you be quiet!
¡Ya basta!
"Be quiet"? What the heck, Shin-chan?
¿Ya basta? ¿Qué te pasa, Shin?
No, I was talking about the doorbell!
No, me refería al timbre de la puerta.
Someone's here to collect the newspaper subscription!
Debe ser por el periódico.
Can we do this later? I'm busy right now!
¿Puede ser más tarde? Estoy ocupado.
Shin-chan!
¡Shin!
Shin-chan, what's going on?
¿Qué sucede, Shin?
What a surprise. I can't believe Kyonkyon has a boyfriend!
Qué sorpresa. No puede creer que Kyon-Kyon tenga novio.
Me either.
Yo tampoco.
You really can't underestimate anyone.
No se puede subestimar a nadie.
So should we go get some tea?
¿Entonces vamos por un poco de té?
Oh, Fujiko-san... the thing is, I'm actually...
Escucha, Fujiko... Lo que pasa es que yo...
What the hell are you doing?
¿Qué diablos haces?
Hanazono-san!
¡Hanazono!
F-Fujiko-san!
¡Fujiko!
I couldn't get out... of my training.
No podía salir del entrenamiento.
Congratulations!
¡Felicitaciones!
For me?
¿Para mí?
I kept it in my breast pocket, so it might smell sweaty.
Estaba en mi pecho así que podría tener un poco de sudor.
It smells nice!
¡Huele delicioso!
How wonderful.
Qué maravilloso.
This might be an unclean vehicle, but please hop on.
No es un gran vehículo, pero sube, por favor.
O-Okay.
Sí.
Um... B-But... Inokuma-san is still...
Pero... Inokuma...
Don't worry about me.
No te preocupes por mí.
But...
Pero...
Oh, you two can ride the bicycle.
Ustedes dos pueden usar la bicicleta.
I'll run alongside. It'll be good training.
Yo correré a su lado. Será un buen entrenamiento.
Really, I'll be fine!
En verdad, no hay problema.
But...
Pero...
I got it! You're waiting for Matsuda-san!
¡Ahora entiendo! ¡Estás esperando a Matsuda!
Matsuda-san? N-No, I'm not!
¿A Matsuda? No, te equivocas.
I see. So it's Matsuda-san.
Ya veo. Así que se trataba de Matsuda.
I can be so dumb!
¡Qué tonta soy!
You're wrong!
Te equivocas.
See you later!
¡Hasta luego!
Don't worry. We'll stay out of your way!
No te preocupes, no te estorbaremos.
You've got it all wrong. God!
Lo malinterpretaste todo.
I hope it all goes as well as a judo match!
Espero que te vaya tan bien como en un encuentro de judo.
I'm telling you...
Pero te digo que...
Don't be so stubborn!
¡No seas tan terca!
Fight on, Inokuma!
¡Ánimo, Inokuma!
Yahoo!
¡Viva!
No winning on points! Score an Ippon!
¡No ganes por puntos! ¡Busca el ippon!
I'm not waiting for Matsuda-san!
No estoy esperando a Matsuda.
I'm sorry you had to drive me home.
Gracias por traerme a casa.
You must be tired. You'd better get some rest.
Debes estar cansada. Duerme bien.
Okay. I'll see you again.
Sí. Nos vemos luego.
Yawara-san!
¡Yawara!
Yes?
¿Sí?
You're finally graduating, aren't you?
Al fin te gradúas, ¿no es así?
I'll definitely come and pick you up after the ceremony.
Sin falta iré a recogerte después de la ceremonia.
We'll celebrate at a five-star restaurant, just the two of us.
Celebraremos en un restaurante, los dos solos.
Will three o'clock at the gate be all right?
¿A las tres en punto en la entrada?
Of course! I'd be happy to!
Sí. Encantada.
I'll see you.
Nos vemos.
Kazamatsuri-san...
Kazamatsuri...
God, you're late!
¡Llegas tarde!
I'm sorry!
¡Lo siento!
Geez, everyone else got picked up. That girl and I were the only ones left!
Cielos, todas ya se fueron. Esa chica y yo éramos las únicas que quedaban.
Wow, so she's still waiting for someone?
¿Entonces todavía espera a alguien?
What happened to Kazamatsuri-san?
¿Qué le habrá sucedido a Kazamatsuri?
He's not picking up his phone.
No contesta al teléfono.
Now that we at Tsurukame Travel have hired Inokuma Yawara-san,
Ahora que en Viajes Tsurukame contratamos a Yawara Inokuma,
we are certainly flying high.
en verdad volaremos alto.
Are you ready for this?
¿Están preparados para esto?
Huh?
¿Qué?
You have in your hand the jewel of Japanese sports... no, of international sports.
Tienen en sus manos a la joya del deporte japonés, no, del deporte mundial.
If you try to milk Yawara-san as an advertising gimmick till she's crushed,
Si intentas exprimir a Yawara como un truco publicitario hasta que no pueda más,
you'll be sorry!
¡me las pagarás!
Stop that!
¡Detente!
If we give up Yawara-san to these people,
Si dejamos a Yawara con estas personas,
a gold medal for her in Barcelona will be just a dream!
la medalla de oro en Barcelona será sólo un sueño.
That's your dream.
No es su sueño, sino el tuyo.
You're damn right it's my dream!
¡Por supuesto que es mi sueño!
And I'll keep chasing that dream and Yawara-san!
¡Y seguiré persiguiendo ese sueño y a Yawara!
He's only trying to write an article.
Sólo le interesa escribir artículos.
He's bothering me just to see if he can get a scoop.
Me molesta para ver si conseguirá una exclusiva.
C-Congratulations...
Felicitaciones...
on getting your degree.
... por graduarte.
Thank you.
Gracias.
She does have the wrong idea.
Piensa mal de mí.
Well, I did say all that stuff without thinking.
Bueno, yo dije todo eso sin pensar.
Here it comes.
Ahí viene.
What is it this time?
¿Qué será esta vez?
"What are your ambitions now that you've entered the workforce?"
¿Cuáles son tus ambiciones ahora que ingresaste al mundo laboral?
It is certainly my dream for Yawara-san to get the gold at Barcelona.
En verdad es mi sueño que Yawara consiga el oro en Barcelona.
You're always going after the next article, Matsuda-san.
Siempre buscas el próximo artículo, Matsuda.
B-But that's not all.
Pero eso no es todo.
You don't have a clue.
No entiendes nada.
My feelings...
Mis sentimientos...
You don't care how I feel.
No te importa lo que siento.
I...
Yo...
Y-Yawara-san!
¡Yawara!
I... know what I said the other day.
Sé lo que dije el otro día.
It's not what I really meant. That was...
No es lo que en verdad pienso. Eso fue...
How should I put this? I was...
¿Cómo decirlo? Eso fue...
Inokuma Yawara!
¡Yawara Inokuma!
H-Honami Sayaka?!
¡¿Sayaka Honami?!
It is time to settle our feud.
Es hora de resolver nuestra disputa.
Right now.
Ahora mismo.
At the All-Japan Judo Championships.
En el Campeonato Nacional de Judo.
Kazamatsuri-san...
Kazamatsuri...
Let us put an end... to this petty gamesmanship.
Pongamos un fin a las tretas y el juego sucio.
You will fight me directly, fair and square,
Te enfrentarás a mí directamente, @en igualdad de condiciones,
Inokuma Yawara.
Yawara Inokuma.
Kazamatsuri-san...
Kazamatsuri...
Sign: The Barcelona Olympics in 166 Days#
#Faltan 166 días para #los Juegos Olímpicos de Barcelona.
So Miss Sayaka has finally come back!
¡Así que la señorita Sayaka finalmente regresó!
Matsuda-san is always talking about judo.
Matsuda siempre está hablando de judo.
When it comes to me, it's always about what will make a good headline.
Cuando se me acerca, siempre es para obtener un buen titular.
Yawara! Now that our heiress is back,
¡Yawara! Ahora que la señorita regresó,
there's no time for gallivanting around as an office girl.
no puedes perder el tiempo revoloteando en la oficina.
Still, why is Kazamatsuri-san with Sayaka-san?
¿Pero por qué Kazamatsuri está con Sayaka?
I swear, men are full of it!
¡Lo juro, los hombres son unos mentirosos!
Yawara!
¡Yawara!
First Kiss!
¡Él primer beso!
Wh-What?!
¡¿Qué?!
You ain't near ready for any kissing! First Kiss!
Te falta mucho para siquiera pensar en besar.